# 今天我們去摘點那個萢子 就在那上面一點點
Today, we gonna pick some berries. They're just a tiny little bit up there.
# 應該現在快熟啦
I think they will be ripe very soon.
# 你看 現開始始種田了
Look! They've already started farming.
# 全部田都已經打好啦 (註︰不懂種田，不明白，是不是翻土的意思)
The soil has all been plowed.
# 坐等插秧 (註︰又不懂，有人懂種田的嗎？)
The next step is transplanting the seedlings.
# 你看 這個萢子 這種
Look! This berry, this type...
# 嗯
Um!
# 好香啊
It smells really nice!
# 淡淡的香味
It's a subtle fragrance.
# 草莓的味道
It tastes like strawberries,
# 比草莓的香味還香
but the fragrance is more significant than strawberries.
# 就是
Only,
# 缺點就是太小啦
if they could have been bigger.
# 你看 這裡有一個
Look! Here is one!
# 挺漂亮的哦
It's rather pretty, isn't it?
# 你看
Look!
# 這就是小時候最歡吃的
These used to be my most favourite snacks when I was a kid.
# 我記得還小的時候
I still remember when I was a kid,
# 天天 天天都去摘這個
we went to pick these berries every, every day.
# 早上一起來就去摘哦
We needed to come really early.
# 要不然 冕去一點就沒有了
Otherwise, if we came just a bit late, nothing would be left.
# 還可以哦
It's not bad.
# 這種
It's,
# 這種跟草莓差不多
it's not so much different from strawberries.
# 不過這個有籽
But it has seeds,
# 草莓是沒籽的
while strawberries don't have any seeds.
# 味道比草莓還好吃
It tastes even better than strawberries.
# 就是少了一點
But there'are not too many of them.
# 少了一點
not too many.
# 你看這個 是最漂亮的哦 最大的
Have a look at this one! This is the prettiest, and the biggest.
# 跟我的腳趾頭那麼大的
It's as big as the tip of my toe.
# 好甜啊這種大的
These big ones are really sweet.
# 就是找不到那麼
But there just aren't too many.
# 可能 一趟下來就找個幾個
Perhaps, I might get a few every time I come here.
# 剛剛有幾個 拍都沒拍就被我吃掉了
There were a few over there. But I'm already put them in my mouth before starting the camera.
# 現在再去找一下 看還有沒有
Let's search again, and see if there are any more.
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 好過癮啊 這一大片都是
It's so cool! Here the berries are everywhere.
# 本來說拿個袋子來裝的
I wanted to come with a bag.
# 算了
Forget it.
# 放在嘴巴上快一點
Putting them right into the mouth saves much time.
# 特別那種
Especially the ones,
# 紅得發黑的那種才好吃
the dark red ones, they're real delicious.
# 好香啊 這種
It smells really good, this one.
# 你看
Look!
# 這個 啊 這個
This one, ah! This one,
# 長得太急啦 你看 長那麼大
it's too eager to grow. Look! It's so big.
# 這個壞的 不要
It's rotten. Pass!
# 哎呀 這粒好大的哦
Aya! This one is really big!
# 一片一片的
They're in bunches.
# 這個小的
Here's a small one.
# 真舒服
Cool!
# 特別這個
Especially this one,
# 這個是最香的
its fragrance is the most significant.
# 你看 這個
Look! This one,
# 這還不是很熟
it's still a bit green.
# 要挑大的
I want the big ones.
# 這裡有
Here,
# 這兩顆
here are two.
# 你看
Look!
# 吃這種萢子要這樣子吃才爽
Let me show you the most exciting way to enjoy these berries.
# 嗯~
Um~
# 太美味啦
Best of the best!
# 看下還有沒有 再找一下
Let's search again, and see if there are any more.
# 都不過癮
It's far from enough.
# 這個大小啦 這個
This is too small, this one.
# 好啦 今天的視頻到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 肚腩都吃出來啦
My tummy is already coming out.
# 哎呦
Ayo!
# 吃太飽啦
I've eaten too much.